<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Bloging n' Stuff]]></title>
  <link href="http://torefranzen.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://torefranzen.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-09-04T01:04:57-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://torefranzen.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tore Franzen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intro to Hacking the BrewPi]]></title>
    <link href="http://torefranzen.github.io/blog/2016/09/04/hacking-the-brewpi-intro/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-04T00:29:17-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://torefranzen.github.io/blog/2016/09/04/hacking-the-brewpi-intro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Intro</h2>

<p>For those that don&rsquo;t know, <a href="http://www.brewpi.com/">BrewPi</a> is the answer to modern man&rsquo;s problem of controlling Beer fermentation temperature. Originally, it was a Raspberry Pi coupled with an Arduino (and more currently a Photon Spark). The Arduino (or Spark) acts as the work horse of the operation by measuring temperature and controlling heat and/or cooling for the fermentation chamber. The Raspberry Pi would act as a web server, displaying information and sending commands to the Arduino (or Spark). The creators of the project have also kindly posted their code in git hub <a href="https://github.com/BrewPi">https://github.com/BrewPi</a>.</p>

<h2>WTF Are you trying to do? The thing works already!</h2>

<p>What I would like to do is remove the Arduino and still have a functioning setup. Initially, this looks like it might take some time and thought. I want to do this as a learning experiment. There is no intention on sabotaging the efforts of the BrewPi team. They rightfully deserve credit and I have the utmost respect for them and the product they have created.</p>

<p>With all that out of the way, I have come up with a few ideas of how I can make a stand alone BrewPi out of the Raspberry Pi (3):</p>

<ul>
<li>Understand the Arduino/Spark code and rewrite into python code (or something else, i.e. bash) to run in an infinite loop on the pi</li>
<li>Create wrapper code around the existing firmware and simulate on the pi</li>
<li>Something else?</li>
<li>Forget the whole thing and go buy an Arduino</li>
</ul>


<h2>So Whats Next?</h2>

<p>Not much besides delving into the <a href="https://github.com/BrewPi">BrewPi git hub repo</a> and trying to figure out how the darn thing works. So far, I have learned about the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PID_controller">PID algorithm</a> and am currently figuring out how its implemented in the BrewPi. (Note: I have a Computer Science background and not one in electronics or control theory). Hopefully there will be more status updates to come.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last!]]></title>
    <link href="http://torefranzen.github.io/blog/2016/09/04/last/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-04T00:16:57-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://torefranzen.github.io/blog/2016/09/04/last</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This will be the Last post EVER!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
